

Floralb Xhelaj

An enthusiast specialized in web-app development with Angular & .NET Core framework, solving real-world problems using engineering skills with passion for friendly software design, solid architecture, best practices and documentation.

floralb.xhelaj@outlook.com (+355) 68-378-6815 linkedin.com/in/floralb.xhelaj floralbxhh.github.io

EXPERIENCE

Freelancer — Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Aspen Search Engine

Represents a web-scraping system that collects and filter data for Air Conditioners or Heat Pumps.

- 1. Implemented dynamic filtering form using NgRx to display different filter panels.
- 2. Implemented frontend caching technique using IndexDB.
- 3. Deployed frontend using AWS S3 Buckets and backend using Amazon Elastic Beanstalk.
- 4. Setup web-scraping example using Selenium Automation Framework.

Coders SHPK, Albania — Software Engineer

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT

Matriculation Management System

Represents a system that determines high-school students eligible to enroll public universities.

- 1. Architect frontend using Nx workspaces and SSR, thus providing higher scalable infrastructure.
- 2. Implement base CRUD functionality using NgRx component-store and standalone components (lazy-loading, import & export excel).
- 3. Got the opportunity to learn NgRx Store by implementing User authentication flow and providing a centralized store for easier accessibility to user data.
- 4. Implement Role-based access control functionality using Guards, Directives, Pipes in frontend and ASP.NET Identity in backend.
- 5. Setup frontend CI/CD pipelines using Azure Cloud Services.
- Courier Management
 - 1. Built frontend application skeleton using enterprise project structure.
 - 2. Implement CRUD operations using Presentational Container pattern.
 - 3. Gained knowledge of the NgRx component-store library to simplify unidirectional data flow.
- eTax Case Management Module

Represents a workflow engine and decision engine to automate business processes.

- 1. Gained knowledge of Business Process Modeling Notation (BPMN) approach for modeling the steps of a planned business process.
- 2. Practical experience using Nx to simplify micro-frontends architecture using "Module Federation".
- 3. Designed and developed feature to implement dynamic form builder and renderer.
- ${\bf 4.} \quad {\bf Developed\ API\ endpoints\ to\ persist\ user\ forms\ data\ using\ CQRS\ pattern.}$

Used technologies: Angular, ASP.NET Core, Jira, Azure Cloud, Oracle RDBMS, Node.js.

ASystems, Albania — Software Developer

AUGUST 2020 - FEBRUARY 2022

DVR Document Module

CRM Module in which the client creates a DVR Document template and can instantiate documents for different institutions.

- Designed and developed API to persist dynamic and static DVR Document content in a multi-tenant MongoDB
 environment
- $2. \quad \mbox{Gained knowledge of MongoDB}. \mbox{NET API and Azure Blob Storage to store static files}.$
- 3. Implemented versioning logic to be able to upgrade or rollback the document template among multiple versions.
- 4. Implemented major feature to render dynamic configured input control forms and user guidance on configuring dynamic forms.
- Internal Survey
 - 1. Internal project to create and manage surveys and analyze respondents answers.
 - 2. Implemented feature to display respondent's answers and automate correction based on answers template.
 - 3. Automation of email notifications using Hangfire as a background job scheduler.
 - 4. Codebase refactoring and migration to newer version of Angular.
- Fitblast API
 - 1. Developed Fitblast API (mobile game) to persist user data and personal progress during the game.
 - 2. Gained knowledge of the Firestore .NET API for non-relational data and Firebase Authentication to manage users authentication.

Used technologies: Angular, ASP.NET Core, MongoDB, Firebase, Azure Cloud, SQL Server.

Soft&Solution, Albania — Software Developer

MARCH 2019 - AUGUST 2020

- e-Albania
 - 1. Government platform for promoting electronic services for citizens, businesses, and state administration.
 - 2. Designed and developed SOAP web services for A2A (application-to-application) communication and interfacing.
 - 3. Database maintenance using stored procedures and Profilers to monitor query performances using SQL Server.
 - 4. Maintaining and upgrading existing systems that monitor workflow steps for e-Albania user's applications.
- "Banesat sociale"
 - 1. State system to provide housing option for people across the country.
 - 2. Database maintenance and creating stored procedures to automate some of the application's workflow steps.
 - 3. Maintaining existing workflow module.

Used Technologies: ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server, Razor, Bootstrap4, jQuery.

EDUCATION

Master of Science – Computer Science

Faculty of Natural Sciences, University of Tirana - Albania 2020 – Present

Bachelor – Computer Science

Faculty of Natural Sciences, University of Tirana - Albania 2017 - 2020